<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="CV.xslt" type="text/xsl" ?>
<cv>
	<me
		name="Mr Tauhid Mahmood"
		address="44 Rowliff Road, High Wycombe, Buckinghamshire, HP12 3LD"
		telephone="07891 290765"
		email="tauhidm01@outlook.com">
		<p>In a world of technological advancements, I am keen to learn and develop my existing skills, to be part of this exciting period. My interest in Computing has continued to grow as I have watched and been part of an ever-evolving and developing industry where I have been surrounded by technological advancements - from the growth of the internet, to the smartphone and the emergence of many social media platforms.</p>
		<p>I am a dedicated, organized and methodical individual. I have good interpersonal skills, am an excellent team worker and am keen and very willing to learn and develop new skills. I have an active and dynamic approach to work and getting things done as I am determined and decisive.</p>
	</me>
	<education>
		<qualification
	establishment="Buckinghamshire New University"
	type="Degree"
	from="2007"
	to="2009">
			Bachelors<strong>First Class Honours</strong> in the degree of <strong>BSc Hons Software Engineering.</strong>
		</qualification>

		<qualification
	establishment="Sir William Ramsay School Sixth Form"
	type="A-Levels"
	from="2005"
	to="2007">
			Distinction in <strong>Information Technology</strong><br/>
			Merit in <strong>Business Studies</strong><br/>
			D grade in <strong>A-Level History</strong><br/>
		</qualification>
		
		<qualification
	establishment="Sir William Ramsay School Sixth Form"
	type="A-Levels"
	from="2005"
	to="2007">
			Distinction in <strong>Information Technology</strong><br/>
			Merit in <strong>Business Studies</strong><br/>
			D grade in <strong>A-Level History</strong><br/>
		</qualification>

		<qualification
			establishment="Sir William Ramsay School"
			type="GCSEs"
			from="1999"
			to="2007">
			5 in <strong>Maths</strong><br/>
			6 in <strong>English</strong><br/>
			C in <strong>Science</strong><br/>
			B in <strong>History</strong><br/>
			B in <strong>Philosophy and Ethics</strong><br/>
			Disticntion in <strong>Business Studies</strong><br/>
			Merit in <strong>Information Technology</strong><br/>
		</qualification>
		
	</education>
	
	
	<employment>

		<experience
	establishment="Rav Industries"
	job_title="Software Engineer"
	from="August 2009"
	to="October 2011">
			<description>Application Developer For Financial Services</description>
			<achievement>Developed and designed three critical software programs for financial tracking and reporting whilst implementing AGILE Methodologies.</achievement>
			<achievement>Optimized user effectiveness by creating a detailed feedback queue for users to discuss functionality, convenience, and effectiveness.</achievement>
			<achievement>Oversee a team of four software developers and lead weekly discussions to brainstorm ideas in software development and to track changes made in existing programs.</achievement>
		</experience>
		
		<experience
			establishment="Sky"
			job_title="Junior Software Developer"
			from="November 2011"
			to="October 2013">
			<description>Spent 2 years at the company in which I handled many projects</description>
			<achievement>Now TV a online entertainment streaming service.</achievement>
			<achievement>Developed Mobile app known as Sky GO which is used for streaming television on mobile phones.</achievement>
			<achievement>Created Sky Kids TV an application made for streaming kids tv services.</achievement>
			<achievement>Learned a great deal whilst working at Sky for two years.</achievement>
		</experience>
		
		<experience
			establishment="Clovertech Info Ltd"
			job_title="Python Software Developer Intern"
			from="July 2008"
			to="August 2008">
			<description>Mentored by a Senior Software Engineer which helped me gain an insight into the Software Industry</description>
			<achievement>Projects Handled: Finanical Application For HSBC Bank for mobile banking</achievement>
			<achievement>Technologies Used- Frontend: Python Backend: MySQL Database.</achievement>
			<achievement>Learned a great deal whilst here as I worked alongside a team of 7 Software Developers</achievement>
			</experience>

		<experience
		establishment="Financial Software Corps"
		job_title="Python Developer Intern"
		from="December 2013"
		to="Present">
			<description>Working here on Application development and maintenance</description>
			<achievement>Projects Handled: Indus Collection which is an online payment system, API Application for Taxi Company.</achievement>
			<achievement>Technologies Used- Frontend: Python Backend: MySQL Database.</achievement>
			<achievement>Learned a great deal whilst working at Clovertech and have further developed my knowledge.</achievement>
		</experience>
	</employment>
	
	<hobandint>
		<p>I enjoy partaking in a wide range of sports in my free time such as, Football, Tennis, Swimming etc.</p>
		<p>I am really fond of creating web based applications in my spare time in order to develop my knowledge.</p>
		<p>Also in my spare time I particiapte in trading an hope to purchase a wide range of stocks in the future.</p>
		<p>I enjoy reading non-fiction and fiction books as I beleive reading is a must.</p>
	</hobandint>
	
	<references>
		<contact
			email="skarimiswr@gmail.com"
			telephone="07802 325123"
			relationship="IT Teacher in Sixth Form">
			Soheila Karimi
		</contact>
		<contact
			email="richardsmith01@gmail.com"
			telephone="07898 890761"
			relationship="Lecturer in Bucks New University">
			Dr Richard Smith
		</contact>
	</references>
</cv>